<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>RStudio on Teach Data Science</title>
    <link>https://teachdatascience.com/tags/rstudio/</link>
    <description>Recent content in RStudio on Teach Data Science</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>(c) 2019 Copyright Teach Data Science</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 27 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://teachdatascience.com/tags/rstudio/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Using Shiny in the Classroom</title>
      <link>https://teachdatascience.com/shiny2/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://teachdatascience.com/shiny2/</guid>
      <description>Shiny RecapYesterday we introduced R Shiny and discussed how it allows you to build interactive web applications straight from R. We saw a few examples highlighting the wondrous interactivity of exploratory data analysis, data visualization, and data models that it enables. If you didn’t catch yesterday’s post, check it out at https://teachdatascience.com/shiny1/ and be sure to go play around with some Shiny apps at RStudio’s gallery at https://shiny.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>An Introduction to R Shiny</title>
      <link>https://teachdatascience.com/shiny1/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://teachdatascience.com/shiny1/</guid>
      <description>What is R Shiny?shiny is a powerful and flexible R package that makes it easy to build interactive web applications and dynamic dashboards straight from R. These apps can be hosted on a standalone webpage or embedded in R Markdown documents. Not only does shiny allow you to build these web apps from R, but it enables their construction using only R code. Knowledge of HTML and web development is not required at all, though it can be used to enhance your apps in numerous ways.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Projects in RStudio</title>
      <link>https://teachdatascience.com/projects/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 May 2019 21:13:14 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://teachdatascience.com/projects/</guid>
      <description>What are Projects?RStudio Projects are a mechanism for keeping all the files associated with a project together in one place – data, R scripts, results, figures, reports, etc. Projects are built in to the RStudio IDE, and for good reproducible workflow, all projects should start by creating a Project.
Why RStudio?It goes almost without saying that as a group we have moved completely to the RStudio interface to R.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introduction: A summer of data science education</title>
      <link>https://teachdatascience.com/intro/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 May 2019 21:13:14 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://teachdatascience.com/intro/</guid>
      <description>Why another Data Science Education blog?This is an exciting time to be teaching students how to extract meaning from data. Amidst the flood of information available in almost all domains there have been a flourishing of powerful, open-source tools to help with the process. For instructors, the many changes can be hard to keep up with. In this blog, we’re hoping to create a roadmap for faculty development that will ease the learning curve and help busy people incorporate new tools and approaches into their teaching.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>