<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>multivariate thinking on Teach Data Science</title>
    <link>https://teachdatascience.com/tags/multivariate-thinking/</link>
    <description>Recent content in multivariate thinking on Teach Data Science</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>(c) 2019 Copyright Teach Data Science</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 09 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://teachdatascience.com/tags/multivariate-thinking/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Using the Common Online Data Analysis Platform (CODAP) to teach data science</title>
      <link>https://teachdatascience.com/codap/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://teachdatascience.com/codap/</guid>
      <description>Today we have a guest entry authored by Tim Erickson (eeps media) and Bill Finzer (Concord Consortium) about the use of the Common Online Data Analysis Platform (CODAP) to teach data science. They write:
We’ve been designing point-and-click data software since the early 90’s. From the beginning, though, we wanted to get beyond point-and-click to a user experience of data immersion. (William Gibson’s 1984 cyberpunk novel Neuromancer and its “cyberspace” both inspired and eluded us.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Guidelines for Assessment and Instruction in Statistics Education</title>
      <link>https://teachdatascience.com/gaise/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Jun 2019 21:13:14 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://teachdatascience.com/gaise/</guid>
      <description>The American Statistical Association has placed a priority on how best to teach statistics and data science. The Guidelines for Assessment and Instruction in Statistics Education (GAISE) reports have served a key role in guiding instructors and institutions in their pedagogical choices.
Two GAISE reports have been written: one focused on statistics at the PreK-12 level and another, revised in 2016, focused on college level courses. In this GAISE blog entry we focus on the college report.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>