<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>tidyverse on Teach Data Science</title>
    <link>https://teachdatascience.com/tags/tidyverse/</link>
    <description>Recent content in tidyverse on Teach Data Science</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>(c) 2019 Copyright Teach Data Science</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 16 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://teachdatascience.com/tags/tidyverse/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>infer</title>
      <link>https://teachdatascience.com/infer/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://teachdatascience.com/infer/</guid>
      <description>Although an agreed upon definition of data science is hard to come by, there is clear consensus that statistics plays a key role in the foundational knowledge of anyone working with data. One important aspect of statistics is understanding of the inferential process that allows claims to be made about a population from a dataset. Most Introductory Statistics courses and textbooks spend substantial time presenting statistical inference as a way to generate p-values and make claims (or not) about a research hypothesis.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Watching an expert work through a data analysis using the tidyverse</title>
      <link>https://teachdatascience.com/screencast/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Jun 2019 21:13:14 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://teachdatascience.com/screencast/</guid>
      <description>Watching an expert work through a data analysis using the tidyverseTeaching Data Science is challenging since it involves teaching the entire data science analysis cycle. While it’s helpful for students to experience this process, they can often feel at sea in terms of the decisions they need to make and the iterative process of exploration, modeling, summarization.
We’ve been using the data science cycle promulgated by Hadley Wickham and Garrett Grolemund (both from RStudio) that was published in their excellent book: R for Data Science, https://r4ds.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Tidyverse</title>
      <link>https://teachdatascience.com/tidyverse/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Jun 2019 21:13:14 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://teachdatascience.com/tidyverse/</guid>
      <description>What is the Tidyverse?The tidyverse is a coherent system of R packages for data wrangling, exploration and visualization that share a common design philosophy. These packages are intended to make statisticians and data scientists more productive by guiding them through workflows that facilitate communication, and result in reproducible work products. Unpacking the tidyverse, all that it means and contains, could easily take a dedicated book or blog in itself.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>