<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>high performance computing on Teach Data Science</title>
    <link>https://teachdatascience.com/tags/high-performance-computing/</link>
    <description>Recent content in high performance computing on Teach Data Science</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>(c) 2019 Copyright Teach Data Science</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 30 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://teachdatascience.com/tags/high-performance-computing/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>More cloud computing: data science is not done on a laptop</title>
      <link>https://teachdatascience.com/cloud2/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://teachdatascience.com/cloud2/</guid>
      <description>Previous blog entries have discussed cloud based servers (RStudio Server and JupyterHub) and parallel/grid/cluster computing. Today we will expand upon these ideas to discuss at a high level how data science students can leverage cloud based tools to undertake their analyses in a flexible manner.
Our discussion is motivated by several recent papers and blog posts that describe how complex, real-world data science computation can be structured in ways that would not have been feasible in past years without herculean efforts.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Parallel processing and sparklyr</title>
      <link>https://teachdatascience.com/parallel/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://teachdatascience.com/parallel/</guid>
      <description>Today’s blog entry is on parallel and grid computing. As a data science education blog, our focus is more on how to discuss ways to help students learn about high performance computing in the classroom rather than parallel computing for particular research projects (for a recent example see “Ambitious data science can be painless”). Early on in data science education it’s important to develop a foundation and precursors for future work.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
