<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>collaboration on Teach Data Science</title>
    <link>https://teachdatascience.com/tags/collaboration/</link>
    <description>Recent content in collaboration on Teach Data Science</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>(c) 2019 Copyright Teach Data Science</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 24 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://teachdatascience.com/tags/collaboration/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Algorithmic Bias</title>
      <link>https://teachdatascience.com/algbias/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://teachdatascience.com/algbias/</guid>
      <description>Many of you are likely to have been following the recent news (see here and here and here and here for recent articles) on facial recognition software, its use in the criminal justice system, and the systematic racial biases associated with facial recognition. You may also be aware of other algorithms which are systematically biased against a particular group of people.


However, you may not have a plan for how to bring the ideas into the data science classroom.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Python Community</title>
      <link>https://teachdatascience.com/pycomm/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://teachdatascience.com/pycomm/</guid>
      <description>All week we’ve been celebrating using Python in data science. There is no question that Python is a fantastic and very powerful language. Additionally, it is typically thought of as clearly the most used language for doing data science. The kaggle 2017 survey reports that more than three-quarters of data scientists use Python (although they also mention that most statisticians use R).


Knowing how to use Python is an important first step to engaging with the software.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>reprex:  Help me help you</title>
      <link>https://teachdatascience.com/reprex/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://teachdatascience.com/reprex/</guid>
      <description>…if you give a man a fish he is hungry again in an hour. If you teach him to catch a fish you do him a good turn.
The quote is often attributed to a Chinese proverb and is excerpted from Anne Isabella Thackeray Ritchie’s novel, Mrs. Dymond (1885). The point is well understood – one of the most important things we can teach our students is how they can help themselves.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Five quick tips for coding in the classroom</title>
      <link>https://teachdatascience.com/teaching_programming_tips/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://teachdatascience.com/teaching_programming_tips/</guid>
      <description>IntroHello!It’s my distinct pleasure to be guest-blogging for you today! My name is Kelly Bodwin and I’m an Assistant Professor of Statistics at Cal Poly, San Luis Obispo. In my two years at Cal Poly I have taught
Stat 218 - An introductory course for non-majorsStat 419 - An upper-level course in multivariate analysisStat 331 - Our department’s introductory R classIn all of these courses, I make extensive use of R.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Style Guides for Coding</title>
      <link>https://teachdatascience.com/styleguide/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://teachdatascience.com/styleguide/</guid>
      <description>The Importance of Good Coding StyleTo begin with another quote from Hadley Wickham: “Good coding style is like using correct punctuation. You can manage without it, but it sure makes things easier to read.” In this way, coding style is very much an example of a negative virtue. You are much more likely to be told if you have a bad coding style than you are if you have a good coding style.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Data Science for Good</title>
      <link>https://teachdatascience.com/data4good/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://teachdatascience.com/data4good/</guid>
      <description>As educators, it is exciting that our course enrollments are up and students are excited about data science topics, models, software, and careers. It is also validating that when they graduate, our students are able to support themselves doing interesting and engaging work. However, it can be sometimes disheartening to realize how many of our data science students use their skills to maximize the number of times viewers click on ads.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using GitHub in R</title>
      <link>https://teachdatascience.com/githubinr/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://teachdatascience.com/githubinr/</guid>
      <description>Once you get the hang of using Projects in RStudio, you may be inclined to collaborate with others on the same project. If so, you will want to set up a Project that links directly to GitHub. By having your project on GitHub (and regularly saving it / updating it on GitHub), your collaborators will always have access to the most up to date analysis information.
Previous posts have described working with R Projects and working with GitHub.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using GitHub in R</title>
      <link>https://teachdatascience.com/githubinr.utf8/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://teachdatascience.com/githubinr.utf8/</guid>
      <description>Once you get the hang of using Projects in RStudio, you may be inclined to collaborate with others on the same project. If so, you will want to set up a Project that links directly to GitHub. By having your project on GitHub (and regularly saving it / updating it on GitHub), your collaborators will always have access to the most up to date analysis information.
Previous posts have described working with R Projects and working with GitHub.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>GitHub for Fun and Profit</title>
      <link>https://teachdatascience.com/github/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://teachdatascience.com/github/</guid>
      <description>How do we help students carry out data analysis workflows that are comprehensible and reproducible?
The 2018 NASEM “Data Science for Undergraduates” report enunciated the importance of workflow and reproducibility as a key component of data acumen.
“Documenting and sharing workflows enable others to understand how data have been used and refined and what steps were taken in an analysis process. This can increase the confidence in results and improve trust in the process as well as enable reuse of analyses or results in a meaningful way” (NASEM 2019, page 2-12).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>GitHub for Fun and Profit</title>
      <link>https://teachdatascience.com/github.utf8/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://teachdatascience.com/github.utf8/</guid>
      <description>How do we help students carry out data analysis workflows that are comprehensible and reproducible?
The 2018 NASEM &amp;laquo;Data Science for Undergraduates&amp;raquo; report enunciated the importance of workflow and reproducibility as a key component of data acumen.
 &amp;laquo;Documenting and sharing workflows enable others to understand how data have been used and refined and what steps were taken in an analysis process. This can increase the confidence in results and improve trust in the process as well as enable reuse of analyses or results in a meaningful way&amp;raquo; (NASEM 2019, page 2-12).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Projects in RStudio</title>
      <link>https://teachdatascience.com/projects/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 May 2019 21:13:14 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://teachdatascience.com/projects/</guid>
      <description>What are Projects?RStudio Projects are a mechanism for keeping all the files associated with a project together in one place – data, R scripts, results, figures, reports, etc. Projects are built in to the RStudio IDE, and for good reproducible workflow, all projects should start by creating a Project.
Why RStudio?It goes almost without saying that as a group we have moved completely to the RStudio interface to R.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>