<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>collaboration on Teach Data Science</title>
    <link>https://teachdatascience.com/tags/collaboration/</link>
    <description>Recent content in collaboration on Teach Data Science</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>(c) 2019 Copyright Teach Data Science</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 12 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://teachdatascience.com/tags/collaboration/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Using GitHub in R</title>
      <link>https://teachdatascience.com/2019/06/12/githubinr/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://teachdatascience.com/2019/06/12/githubinr/</guid>
      <description>Once you get the hang of using Projects in RStudio, you may be inclined to collaborate with others on the same project. If so, you will want to set up a Project that links directly to GitHub. By having your project on GitHub (and regularly saving it / updating it on GitHub), your collaborators will always have access to the most up to date analysis information.
Previous posts have described working with R Projects and working with GitHub.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Github for Fun and Profit</title>
      <link>https://teachdatascience.com/2019/06/11/github/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://teachdatascience.com/2019/06/11/github/</guid>
      <description>How do we help students carry out data analysis workflows that are comprehensible and reproducible?
The 2018 NASEM “Data Science for Undergraduates” report enunciated the importance of workflow and reproducibility as a key component of data acumen.
“Documenting and sharing workflows enable others to understand how data have been used and refined and what steps were taken in an analysis process. This can increase the confidence in results and improve trust in the process as well as enable reuse of analyses or results in a meaningful way” (NASEM 2019, page 2-12).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Projects in RStudio</title>
      <link>https://teachdatascience.com/2019/05/30/projects/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 May 2019 21:13:14 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://teachdatascience.com/2019/05/30/projects/</guid>
      <description>What are Projects?RStudio Projects are a mechanism for keeping all the files associated with a project together in one place – data, R scripts, results, figures, reports, etc. Projects are built in to the RStudio IDE, and for good reproducible workflow, all projects should start by creating a Project.
Why RStudio?It goes almost without saying that as a group we have moved completely to the RStudio interface to R.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>