<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>R Markdown on Teach Data Science</title>
    <link>https://teachdatascience.com/tags/r-markdown/</link>
    <description>Recent content in R Markdown on Teach Data Science</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 18 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://teachdatascience.com/tags/r-markdown/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Less Volume More Creativity in R</title>
      <link>https://teachdatascience.com/mosaic/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://teachdatascience.com/mosaic/</guid>
      <description>In 2016, GAISE enunciated the importance of multivariate thinking and technology when teaching introductory statistics and data science courses. A big challenge is how to do this using R and RStudio without running into cognitive overload with our students.
The mosaic package was created by Randall Pruim, Danny Kaplan, and Nicholas Horton with the goal of introducing a Less Volume, More Creativity approach to introductory statistics that could simplify the use of technology.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SQL 101 in R</title>
      <link>https://teachdatascience.com/sql/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://teachdatascience.com/sql/</guid>
      <description>The NASEM Data Science for Undergraduates report noted that the storage, preparation, and accessing of data is at the heart of data science and that students need to directly experience multiple forms of data, including the use of databases.
SQL (pronounced sequel) stands for Structured Query Language; it is a language designed to manage data in a relational database system. The papers https://chance.amstat.org/2015/04/setting-the-stage and https://chance.amstat.org/2015/04/databases/ provide a high level overview of database systems.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Github Classroom</title>
      <link>https://teachdatascience.com/gitclass/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://teachdatascience.com/gitclass/</guid>
      <description>GitHub ClassroomIf you have been reading along in the blog, you’ve noticed the last two entries describing GitHub and GitHub in R. And certainly, we continue to advocate teaching students to use GitHub as an integral part of their data science workflow. And GitHub may be the perfect place to store student projects either as public or private repositories.
But using GitHub to navigate a dozen homework assignments with 50 students can become logistically difficult.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using GitHub in R</title>
      <link>https://teachdatascience.com/githubinr/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://teachdatascience.com/githubinr/</guid>
      <description>Once you get the hang of using Projects in RStudio, you may be inclined to collaborate with others on the same project. If so, you will want to set up a Project that links directly to GitHub. By having your project on GitHub (and regularly saving it / updating it on GitHub), your collaborators will always have access to the most up to date analysis information.
Previous posts have described working with R Projects and working with GitHub.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Leaflet for mapping</title>
      <link>https://teachdatascience.com/leaflet/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://teachdatascience.com/leaflet/</guid>
      <description>Leaflet for mappingMaps are an important way of displaying data.
The leaflet package in R provides access to the Leaflet Javascript libraries (http://leafletjs.com), an open-source mechanism to create interactive maps. The leaflet package (https://rstudio.github.io/leaflet/) provides an interface within R that allows for composing maps using map tiles (e.g., from OpenStreetMap, https://www.openstreetmap.org/#map=5/38.007/-95.844) that can be annotated with markers, lines, popups.
Here’s a simple example where data from higher education institutions from within the Five College Consortium in Western Massachusetts is mapped.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Guidelines for Assessment and Instruction in Statistics Education</title>
      <link>https://teachdatascience.com/gaise/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Jun 2019 21:13:14 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://teachdatascience.com/gaise/</guid>
      <description>The American Statistical Association has placed a priority on how best to teach statistics and data science. The Guidelines for Assessment and Instruction in Statistics Education (GAISE) reports have served a key role in guiding instructors and institutions in their pedagogical choices.
Two GAISE reports have been written: one focused on statistics at the PreK-12 level and another, revised in 2016, focused on college level courses. In this GAISE blog entry we focus on the college report.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Watching an expert work through a data analysis using the tidyverse</title>
      <link>https://teachdatascience.com/screencast/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Jun 2019 21:13:14 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://teachdatascience.com/screencast/</guid>
      <description>Watching an expert work through a data analysis using the tidyverseTeaching Data Science is challenging since it involves teaching the entire data science analysis cycle. While it’s helpful for students to experience this process, they can often feel at sea in terms of the decisions they need to make and the iterative process of exploration, modeling, summarization.
We’ve been using the data science cycle promulgated by Hadley Wickham and Garrett Grolemund (both from RStudio) that was published in their excellent book: R for Data Science, https://r4ds.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Tidyverse</title>
      <link>https://teachdatascience.com/tidyverse/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Jun 2019 21:13:14 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://teachdatascience.com/tidyverse/</guid>
      <description>What is the Tidyverse?The tidyverse is a coherent system of R packages for data wrangling, exploration and visualization that share a common design philosophy. These packages are intended to make statisticians and data scientists more productive by guiding them through workflows that facilitate communication, and result in reproducible work products. Unpacking the tidyverse, all that it means and contains, could easily take a dedicated book or blog in itself.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Projects in RStudio</title>
      <link>https://teachdatascience.com/projects/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 May 2019 21:13:14 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://teachdatascience.com/projects/</guid>
      <description>What are Projects?RStudio Projects are a mechanism for keeping all the files associated with a project together in one place – data, R scripts, results, figures, reports, etc. Projects are built in to the RStudio IDE, and for good reproducible workflow, all projects should start by creating a Project.
Why RStudio?It goes almost without saying that as a group we have moved completely to the RStudio interface to R.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Getting Started With R Markdown</title>
      <link>https://teachdatascience.com/rmarkdown/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 May 2019 21:13:14 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://teachdatascience.com/rmarkdown/</guid>
      <description>What is R Markdown?Straight from RStudio’s wonderful tutorial, R Markdown is an authoring framework for data science. An R Markdown file is a plain text file with three types of content: code chunks to run, text to display, and metadata to help govern the R Markdown build process. Put simply, R Markdown is an exciting new reporting medium that seamlessly integrates executable code and expository text.
By including data work, code, and analysis narrative into a single document, R Markdown provides a fully reproducible vehicle for data science projects!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ingesting Data</title>
      <link>https://teachdatascience.com/ingestingdata/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 May 2019 21:13:14 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://teachdatascience.com/ingestingdata/</guid>
      <description>Why use data from outside sources?The world is awash in data, and whatever else we teach in a data science curriculum, data must be at the center. Calls to modernize statistics and data science courses regularly point to using “real” data. The National Academies Report on Data Science for Undergraduates (see previous blog post at: https://teachdatascience.com/nasem/) reports Data Management &amp;amp; Curation as a core part of data acumen. Indeed, they recognize data provenance to be a key skill which is “important for all students in [a] data science program.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>