<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>statistics on Teach Data Science</title>
    <link>https://teachdatascience.com/tags/statistics/</link>
    <description>Recent content in statistics on Teach Data Science</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>(c) 2019 Copyright Teach Data Science</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 29 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://teachdatascience.com/tags/statistics/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>One model to rule them all</title>
      <link>https://teachdatascience.com/onemodel/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://teachdatascience.com/onemodel/</guid>
      <description>As we near the end of our summer posts, we’ve started to think more broadly about statistics as well as data science courses. Today’s post considers a broad question relevant for many courses: how can we teach statistical thinking without having to resort to introducing a profusion of tests?
Jonas Kristoffer Lindeløv proposed an elegant approach using the idea that common statistical tests are linear models.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The conversation around p-values</title>
      <link>https://teachdatascience.com/pvals/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://teachdatascience.com/pvals/</guid>
      <description>Image credit: xkcd.comStatistics for scienceFiguring out truth is really hard to do. Teaching students how to attempt it may be even harder. As statisticians we know that statistical significance isn’t truth, but we still hope that the process by which we analyze data will lead us on a path toward scientific discovery. How do we teach students the best way to stay on the path of using statistics to move science forward?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Undergraduate Curriculum Guidelines</title>
      <link>https://teachdatascience.com/pcmi/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://teachdatascience.com/pcmi/</guid>
      <description>Throughout the summer 2019 blog series, we have given teaching tips, best data science practices, links to compilations of papers in data science and in teaching data science, and ways to participate in the larger data science community. That is, for anyone already working in a data science community (e.g., in a job or an academic institution) or for anyone doing data science for fun, we have provided myriad rabbit holes in which to get lost for your entire summer.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Teaching Data Visualization</title>
      <link>https://teachdatascience.com/dataviz/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://teachdatascience.com/dataviz/</guid>
      <description>As statistics educators, it is often easier to focus our teaching on methods instead of communication. And while many of us understand the value of good communication, actually teaching it is difficult and outside of our comfort zone. There has been quite a bit of work done on the science of visualization (e.g., the Grammar of Graphics by Wilkinson). There is general consensus that teaching students to communicate using visualizations is of paramount importance (see recent blog entries: National Academies Report on Data Science and GAISE).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Less Volume More Creativity in R</title>
      <link>https://teachdatascience.com/mosaic/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://teachdatascience.com/mosaic/</guid>
      <description>In 2016, GAISE enunciated the importance of multivariate thinking and technology when teaching introductory statistics and data science courses. A big challenge is how to do this using R and RStudio without running into cognitive overload with our students.
The mosaic package was created by Randall Pruim, Danny Kaplan, and Nicholas Horton with the goal of introducing a Less Volume, More Creativity approach to introductory statistics that could simplify the use of technology.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Less Volume More Creativity in R</title>
      <link>https://teachdatascience.com/mosaic.knit/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://teachdatascience.com/mosaic.knit/</guid>
      <description>In 2016, GAISE enunciated the importance of multivariate thinking and technology when teaching introductory statistics and data science courses. A big challenge is how to do this using R and RStudio without running into cognitive overload with our students.
The mosaic package was created by Randall Pruim, Danny Kaplan, and Nicholas Horton with the goal of introducing a Less Volume, More Creativity approach to introductory statistics that could simplify the use of technology.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>infer</title>
      <link>https://teachdatascience.com/infer/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://teachdatascience.com/infer/</guid>
      <description>Although an agreed upon definition of data science is hard to come by, there is clear consensus that statistics plays a key role in the foundational knowledge of anyone working with data. One important aspect of statistics is understanding of the inferential process that allows claims to be made about a population from a dataset. Most Introductory Statistics courses and textbooks spend substantial time presenting statistical inference as a way to generate p-values and make claims (or not) about a research hypothesis.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Leaflet for mapping</title>
      <link>https://teachdatascience.com/leaflet/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://teachdatascience.com/leaflet/</guid>
      <description>Leaflet for mappingMaps are an important way of displaying data.
The leaflet package in R provides access to the Leaflet Javascript libraries (http://leafletjs.com), an open-source mechanism to create interactive maps. The leaflet package (https://rstudio.github.io/leaflet/) provides an interface within R that allows for composing maps using map tiles (e.g., from OpenStreetMap, https://www.openstreetmap.org/#map=5/38.007/-95.844) that can be annotated with markers, lines, popups.
Here’s a simple example where data from higher education institutions from within the Five College Consortium in Western Massachusetts is mapped.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Watching an expert work through a data analysis using the tidyverse</title>
      <link>https://teachdatascience.com/screencast/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Jun 2019 21:13:14 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://teachdatascience.com/screencast/</guid>
      <description>Watching an expert work through a data analysis using the tidyverseTeaching Data Science is challenging since it involves teaching the entire data science analysis cycle. While it’s helpful for students to experience this process, they can often feel at sea in terms of the decisions they need to make and the iterative process of exploration, modeling, summarization.
We’ve been using the data science cycle promulgated by Hadley Wickham and Garrett Grolemund (both from RStudio) that was published in their excellent book: R for Data Science, https://r4ds.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introduction: A summer of data science education</title>
      <link>https://teachdatascience.com/intro/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 May 2019 21:13:14 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://teachdatascience.com/intro/</guid>
      <description>Why another Data Science Education blog?This is an exciting time to be teaching students how to extract meaning from data. Amidst the flood of information available in almost all domains there have been a flourishing of powerful, open-source tools to help with the process. For instructors, the many changes can be hard to keep up with. In this blog, we’re hoping to create a roadmap for faculty development that will ease the learning curve and help busy people incorporate new tools and approaches into their teaching.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>