<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>education on Teach Data Science</title>
    <link>https://teachdatascience.com/tags/education/</link>
    <description>Recent content in education on Teach Data Science</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>(c) 2019 Copyright Teach Data Science</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 03 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://teachdatascience.com/tags/education/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>The Conversation Around p-values</title>
      <link>https://teachdatascience.com/pvals/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://teachdatascience.com/pvals/</guid>
      <description>Image credit: xkcd.comStatistics for scienceFiguring out truth is really hard to do. Teaching students how to attempt it may be even harder. As statisticians we know that statistical significance isn’t truth, but we still hope that the process by which we analyze data will lead us on a path toward scientific discovery. How do we teach students the best way to stay on the path of using statistics to move science forward?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Undergraduate Curriculum Guidelines</title>
      <link>https://teachdatascience.com/pcmi/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://teachdatascience.com/pcmi/</guid>
      <description>Throughout the summer 2019 blog series, we have given teaching tips, best data science practices, links to compilations of papers in data science and in teaching data science, and ways to participate in the larger data science community. That is, for anyone already working in a data science community (e.g., in a job or an academic institution) or for anyone doing data science for fun, we have provided myriad rabbit holes in which to get lost for your entire summer.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Data Science for Good</title>
      <link>https://teachdatascience.com/data4good/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://teachdatascience.com/data4good/</guid>
      <description>As educators, it is exciting that our course enrollments are up and students are excited about data science topics, models, software, and careers. It is also validating that when they graduate, our students are able to support themselves doing interesting and engaging work. However, it can be sometimes disheartening to realize how many of our data science students use their skills to maximize the number of times viewers click on ads.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>RStudio Server Pro and Rstudio.cloud installations</title>
      <link>https://teachdatascience.com/cloud/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://teachdatascience.com/cloud/</guid>
      <description>When people ask about how to get their students engaged with R in their introductory statistics and data science courses we offer three pieces of advice:
keep it simple (discussed in the “Less Volume, More Creativity” blog entry)engage students to provide peer-tutoring and drop-in office hours to assist with questions and coding to complement class and office hours (at Amherst College this is coordinated by the Statistics and Data Science Fellows)have students use a dedicated server to access RSlide credit: Mine Çetinkaya-Rundel</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pair Programming for Data Science and Statistics</title>
      <link>https://teachdatascience.com/pairprogramming/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://teachdatascience.com/pairprogramming/</guid>
      <description>Pair programming is a technique from software development where two programmers work in tandem to code. One is designated the driver, responsible for typing, while the other, often called the navigator or observer reviews the code and provides a high-level overview of the task.
Photo credit: Esti Alvarez
Pair programming has been thought to lead to better code, more enjoyable coding, and higher productivity, with some research findings supporting those conclusions (see some of the references at the end of this entry).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>infer</title>
      <link>https://teachdatascience.com/infer/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://teachdatascience.com/infer/</guid>
      <description>Although an agreed upon definition of data science is hard to come by, there is clear consensus that statistics plays a key role in the foundational knowledge of anyone working with data. One important aspect of statistics is understanding of the inferential process that allows claims to be made about a population from a dataset. Most Introductory Statistics courses and textbooks spend substantial time presenting statistical inference as a way to generate p-values and make claims (or not) about a research hypothesis.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Github Classroom</title>
      <link>https://teachdatascience.com/gitclass/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://teachdatascience.com/gitclass/</guid>
      <description>GitHub ClassroomIf you have been reading along in the blog, you’ve noticed the last two entries describing GitHub and GitHub in R. And certainly, we continue to advocate teaching students to use GitHub as an integral part of their data science workflow. And GitHub may be the perfect place to store student projects either as public or private repositories.
But using GitHub to navigate a dozen homework assignments with 50 students can become logistically difficult.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Diversity in Data Science &amp; Statistics</title>
      <link>https://teachdatascience.com/diversity/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Jun 2019 21:13:14 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://teachdatascience.com/diversity/</guid>
      <description>Calls for DiversityData science is made up of not only sets of tools, methods, and problems to solve, but also actual people who make up the statistics &amp;amp; data science community. The National Academies Report on Data Science for Undergraduates (see previous blog post at: https://teachdatascience.com/nasem) includes a section on “Ensuring Broad Participation” which reiterates the importance of creating an inclusive community where all views are heard and supported.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introduction: A summer of data science education</title>
      <link>https://teachdatascience.com/intro/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 May 2019 21:13:14 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://teachdatascience.com/intro/</guid>
      <description>Why another Data Science Education blog?This is an exciting time to be teaching students how to extract meaning from data. Amidst the flood of information available in almost all domains there have been a flourishing of powerful, open-source tools to help with the process. For instructors, the many changes can be hard to keep up with. In this blog, we’re hoping to create a roadmap for faculty development that will ease the learning curve and help busy people incorporate new tools and approaches into their teaching.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>